Carlos Guentes wrote, the orange tree is a traveling tree, a natural witness to all human follies.
The tree is the lush, beautiful fruit of the earth, of what is original and essential.
And the earth, continues, Guentes, is different from the world.
The world passes away, but the earth endures and will always take care of us if we allow it to survive.
And that, he says, is the purpose of both literature and life itself, to assure that life goes on, that life does not end.
The story is left unfinished.
This celebration of black girls at this magical, magic ball that we, my dear brothers and sisters, are remembered and endure like the earth.
So I say to you, calling all women, men, children, students, black girls, calling all oceans, skies, clouds, trees, black girls.
This is a peace journey, black girls, magic ball, black girls.
This is an anthology called peace.
No assassins allowed, no wars allowed, no greed allowed, no bullying allowed, no killings allowed, no arguments allowed, no gossip allowed, no homophobia allowed, no racism allowed.
Here, just the slow, quick smell of peace and justice and black girls everywhere, sliding from our tongues, our hands, our eyes, calling all journeymen and journeywomen to this journey of words of churches, schools, universities, homes, countries, cities, of banks and corporations, congress and senate courtrooms and courtyards,
of the white house, prisons and hospitals where men and women sometimes genuflect skeletons, calling all peace warriors and black girls.
Let us genuflect peace, black girls, every day, black girls.
Peace is a human right.
Tony Morrison said we die.
That may be the meaning of life, but we do language.
That may be the measure of our lives.
And my dear sisters, how you do this thing, how you do this thing called life, how you anoint our eyes for surprise and beauty as you bring us into the flesh of rain and laughter called peace, called black girls.
How you do this thing, how you do this thing, called peace and justice and love, love, love, love, love, love, love, love, love.
So I say to you, my dear sisters, on this festive occasion, on this beautiful occasion, on this occasion where we honor each other and our soul, come, come, come, come, come, come, come, come, come, come, come.
Let us flush the world's flesh with peace and love, with peace and love, and live, you black girls all over the world.
Just live, live, live, live, live, live, live, much love to you.
Every while I was thinking about the day, how am I going to do today?
And I think that's one of the things that I attempt to do.
I attempt to wear my days well.
And I want people to learn how to wear their days well.